<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on James Liu</title>
    <link>//jamesliu.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on James Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//jamesliu.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A shallow dive into ADCs</title>
      <link>//jamesliu.io/blog/2020-10-21-a-shallow-dive-into-adcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jamesliu.io/blog/2020-10-21-a-shallow-dive-into-adcs/</guid>
      <description>In the process of designing a digital synthesiser , I spent the weekend learning a little bit about ADCs. This post provides a basic introduction to what they are, and aims to get you familiar with the high level concepts and terminology used in the ADC domain.
An ADC is an Analog-to-Digital Converter; it translates analog signals into digital inputs which your program can interpret.
Analog signals An example of an analog signal you might want to process is the distance you move a thumbstick from its centered position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Salads</title>
      <link>//jamesliu.io/blog/2019-02-09-generating-salads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jamesliu.io/blog/2019-02-09-generating-salads/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a salad place I like called Chia Chia near where I&amp;rsquo;m currently working. I like it for the same reasons I hate it; it epitomises my fear of choice. How so? Here&amp;rsquo;s their salad &amp;ldquo;menu&amp;rdquo;:
Scary isn&amp;rsquo;t it? There are 100 possible combinations of bases alone! Maybe trying out all of the salads here will make it into the bucket list. It&amp;rsquo;ll certainly be quite a gastronomical achievement.
Of course, there are &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; things for a bucket list and trying every possible combination of ingredients would likely produce more than a few inedible salads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a macOS screensaver</title>
      <link>//jamesliu.io/blog/2018-08-05-macos-screensaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jamesliu.io/blog/2018-08-05-macos-screensaver/</guid>
      <description>I tend to browse Hacker News obsessively over the course of a day, and this morning I came across this post where somebody had jailbroken their old Kindle (I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know you could do that 😱) and repurposed it into a fancy clock displaying literary quotes .
I managed to dig up my old second-generation Kindle (which turned 9 this year!) thinking I&amp;rsquo;d charge it up, jailbreak it, and follow along with his tutorial as a fun Sunday morning project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Waterfall, Agile, and Requirements - Part 1</title>
      <link>//jamesliu.io/blog/2018-07-01-waterfall-agile-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jamesliu.io/blog/2018-07-01-waterfall-agile-requirements/</guid>
      <description>I remember sitting in a lecture theatre not too long ago, and being told that 68% of software projects fail . “This is clearly a joke” I thought, “designed to suck us into the next topic we’ll be examined on. How is it that software is ever delivered? How much potential are we losing out on by letting this happen?”.
Fast-forward to the present, and I’m finally beginning to appreciate the values of agile.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
